Hello, everyone.
大家好。
Growing up in my family gives you a certain sense of history.
在我的家族中长大， 可以带给人一定的历史感。
I'm simply the latest in a line that can be traced back generations.
我是我们家族几十代人中的晚辈。
This oak tree is close to Windsor Castle,
这棵橡树靠近温莎城堡，
which has been home to my family for over 900 years.
900 多年间，
Thirty-nine monarchs have lived here and enjoyed these beautiful surroundings.
我的家族有 39 位君主曾居住在此， 欣赏着这些美丽的风景。
I've walked here many times myself,
我曾多次造访这里，
and it always amazes me that some of the trees planted here,
这里的一些树木 总是令我叹为观止。
living organisms, dependent on soil, rain and sunlight,
在温莎堡刚刚破土动工时，
were here as they laid the first stones of Windsor Castle.
它们就已扎根在这里，沐浴阳光雨露。
That makes some of the oaks here almost 1,000 years old.
有些橡树已有近千年的历史了。
These trees germinated during the reign of William the Conqueror in 1066,
1066 年，在征服者威廉统治时期，
from a simple acorn like this.
这些树木就开始 从这样不起眼的橡子中生根发芽。
By the time that Henry VIII lived here,
亨利八世住在这里的时候，
they'd grown into mature, impressive giants.
它们已经长成了参天大树。
And amazingly,
令人惊讶的是，
some of those very same trees still survive here today.
其中有些橡树今天依然存活着。
They're a bit gnarled and hollowed-out,
尽管它们已饱经风霜， 躯干早已残缺不堪，
but they're still very much alive.
但是仍然绽放着顽强的生命力。
While these oaks have been growing,
在这些橡树的生命周期中，
around 35 billion people have lived their lives on our planet.
约有 350 亿人 陆续生活在我们的星球上。
That's 35 billion lifetimes' worth of hope, love, fear and dreams.
那是 350 亿个生命 承载的希望、爱、恐惧和梦想。
In that time, humankind has invented air travel,
在此期间，人类发明了飞机、
vaccines and computers.
疫苗和计算机。
We've explored every part of the globe,
我们已经探索了世界的每个角落，
sequenced the human genome
完成了人类基因组测序，
and even escaped Earth's atmosphere.
甚至成功的冲破了地球的大气层。
Our speed of innovation has been incredible,
我们的创新速度令人难以置信，
but so, too, has the acceleration of our impact.
但是，我们的影响也在加速。
Over my grandmother's lifetime, the last 90 years or so,
在过去 90 年，我祖母的一生中，
our impacts accelerated so fast
我们的影响加速得如此之快 ，
that our climate, oceans, air, nature and all that depends on them
以至于气候、海洋、空气、自然 以及所有依赖于它们的一切，
are in peril.
都陷入了危险之中。
This oak has stood here for centuries,
这棵橡树在这里伫立了几个世纪，
but never has it faced a decade like this.
但它从未经历过这样的十年。
We start this new decade
我们早就知道，
knowing that it is the most consequential period in history.
接下来的十年 是历史上最重要的时期。
The science is irrefutable.
科学结论是无可辩驳的。
If we do not act in this decade,
如果我们在这十年间不采取行动，
the damage that we have done will be irreversible.
我们所造成的破坏将是不可逆转的，
And the effects felt not just by future generations
不仅会影响子孙后代，
but by all of us alive today.
我们这一代人也难以幸免。
And what's more, this damage will not be felt equally by everyone.
而且，这样的破坏 并非对每个人都是平等的。
It is the most vulnerable,
那些最脆弱的、
those with the fewest resources
拥有的资源最少、
and those who've done the least to cause climate change
以及那些对气候影响最小的人，
who will be impacted the most.
受到的冲击却是最大的。
These stark facts are terrifying.
这些严峻的事实令人不寒而栗。
How can we hope to fix such massive intractable problems?
我们应该如何解决 如此庞大而棘手的问题？
It may seem overwhelming, but it is possible.
这虽然令人感到束手无策， 但却依然有一线希望。
Humans have an extraordinary capacity to set goals and strive to achieve them.
人类非常擅长设定目标， 并去努力实现。
I've long been inspired by President John F. Kennedy's
多年以来，我一直 因约翰·肯尼迪总统
1961 mission to put a man on the moon within a decade.
于1961 年宣告的使命而深受鼓舞—— 在十年内将人类送上月球。
He named it the Moonshot.
他将其命名为“登月计划”。
It seemed crazy.
这看似疯狂之举，
We'd only just launched the first satellite.
毕竟当时，我们刚刚 发射了第一颗卫星。
Putting a man on the moon that quickly seemed impossible.
这么快就把人类送上月球， 几乎只是异想天开。
But this simple challenge encompassed so much.
但是这个看似简单的挑战 却意义深远。
He called it a goal to organize and measure
他将其称作组织和衡量
the best of our energies and skills.
人类的能力和技术极限的一个目标。
In taking that giant leap for mankind,
为了人类的巨大飞跃，
the team behind the Moonshot
登月计划背后的团队
united millions of people around the world --
团结了世界各地数百万人。
that this crazy ambition wasn't so crazy after all.
从而让这看似疯狂的雄心 显得不再那么不切实际。
And along the way, it helped the invention of breathing equipment,
一路走来，它推动了
CAT scanners and solar panels.
呼吸设备、CAT扫描仪 和太阳能电池板的发明。
But now, rather than a Moonshot for this decade,
但是现在，我们需要的不再是 一个为期十年的登月计划，
we need Earthshots.
而是“地球计划”。
We must harness that same spirit of human ingenuity and purpose
人类必须利用同样的 创造精神，众志成城，
and turn it with laser sharp focus and urgency
以激光般的精准度 密切关注并紧急应对
on the most pressing challenge we have ever faced,
我们所面临的最紧迫的挑战，
repairing our planet.
修复我们的星球。
The shared goals for our generation are clear.
我们这一代人的共同目标很明确：
Together, we must protect and restore nature,
我们必须共同保护和恢复自然，
clean our air, revive our oceans,
净化空气，清理海洋，
build a waste-free world and fix our climate.
建立一个无浪费的世界，并改善气候。
And we must strive to do all of this in a decade.
而且，我们还必须努力 在十年内实现所有这一切。
If we achieve these goals,
如果到 2030 年， 我们能够实现这些目标，
by 2030 our lives won't be worse,
我们的生活环境就不会继续恶化，
and we won't have to sacrifice everything we enjoy.
也不必牺牲自己热爱的一切。
Instead, the way we live will be healthier,
相反，我们所有人的生活方式 都会更健康、
cleaner, smarter and better for all of us.
更洁净、更智能、更美好。
The global response to the COVID-19 pandemic
全球对新冠肺炎大流行的应对，
and the funds flowing into the economic recovery
为推动经济复苏所投入的资金
demonstrate how much can be achieved
都证明了，
when those in positions of power come together
若当权者凝聚在一起 并决定采取行动时，
and decide to act.
我们可以取得多大的成就。
We built hospitals overnight, repurposed factories,
我们在一夜之间 建造了医院，改造了工厂，
poured billions into the search for a vaccine and better treatments.
投入了数十亿美元研发疫苗 和更好的治疗方法。
And we've been inspired by heroes emerging in every community across the world.
在世界各地的每个社区中， 英雄人物层出不穷。
Young people no longer believe that change is too difficult.
年轻人不再相信 变革是遥不可及的。
They witnessed the world turn on its head.
他们目睹了全世界的改变。
They believe that the climate crisis and the threat to our biodiversity
他们相信，气候危机 以及对我们生物多样性的威胁，
deserves our full attention and ambition.
都应该得到大家的充分重视。
And they're right.
他们是对的。
So now is the time for each one of us to show leadership.
现在是我们每个人 展现领导力的时候了。
Whether you're a farmer in the US,
无论你是美国的农民、
a tech owner in China, a politician in Kenya,
中国的技术所有者、 肯尼亚的政府人士、
a banker in Britain, a fisherman in the Maldives,
英国的银行家、马尔代夫的渔民、
a community leader in Brazil or a student in India,
巴西的社区领袖， 还是印度的学生，
every single one of us has a role to play
我们每个人都能 扮演好自己的角色，
in harnessing whatever opportunity we have.
去抓住我们拥有的任何机会。
I'm committed to using the unique position that I have
我致力于利用自己独特的优势，
to help set those Earthshot goals and reward people
帮助制定“地球计划”的目标，
across every sector of society and in every part of the world
并奖励社会各界以及世界各地
who do their bit to help achieve them.
为实现这些目标做出贡献的人们。
Some people are motivated to act by a crisis,
有些人受危机影响 而不得不采取行动，
but for many,
但是对于许多人来说，
the incentive to act only comes when they believe that change is possible,
采取行动的动机只是因为 他们相信改变是可能的，
that it isn't a lost cause.
我们可以逆转现状。
If people really believe that these challenges,
如果人们真的相信这些挑战，
these Earthshots, are possible,
相信“地球计划”是可行的，
just imagine all the potential we will unleash.
不妨可以想象一下 我们所能释放的所有潜力。
I'm determined to both start and end this decade as an optimist.
我决心以乐观的态度 开启和结束这个十年。
Whilst our generation represents just a blip
虽然在这些宏伟橡树的生命周期中，
in the lifetime of these magnificent oaks,
我们这一代人的寿命 只是一个短暂的瞬间，
we have the power and potential to ensure that they and all life on earth
但我们有力量和潜力， 以确保它们和地球上的所有生命，
thrive for another thousand years and more.
在未来的几千年中 依然可以健康的繁衍生息。
But only if we now unleash the greatest talents of our generation
但前提是，我们现在就要充分发挥出 我们这一代最伟大的才能，
to repair our planet.
来修复我们的星球。
We have no choice but to succeed.
除了成功，我们别无选择。
Thank you.
谢谢。